Frank Izonebi Amungo

16 close B, 64 Crescent Charley Boy road, gwarinpa, Abuja Mobile : 09099590349, 08121745563, E-mail : <u>izonet101@gmail.com</u> SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR, NETWORK ENGINEER (Unix/Linux/ SERVER 2003/2008/2012/2016)

Comp Science (BSc) CCNP, CCNA, CCNAS, RHCSA, MCSA, compTia N+

Network / technical support - Security - IT Support - Customer Services- Trainer - Consulting-Web Developer

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Multi-certified systems and network administrator with more than 10 years' experience managing server infrastructures and data-center operations across Unix, Linux, Windows and Mac OS X platforms, wide breadth of IT support and web development experience. Effectively plan, install, configure and optimize IT network infrastructures to achieve high availability and performance. Excellent and instinctive problem solving and decision making skills with the ability to be proactive in all servers and network system management.

EDUCATION

GATES IT BOOTCAMP: Intense Network & Security training Institute C-8/A, Kasturchad Mills, Mumbai, India. Advance Diploma in ICT- Network Engineering	2008
University of Science and Technology Port Harcourt, Rivers State. BS.c (computer Science).	2005

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING

Cisco Certified Internetwork Expert Data center	In view
Microsoft Certified Solution Expert	In view
Training on Project Management Professional (PMP)	In view
Training on Information Technology Infrastructure library Foundation	2016
Cisco Certified Network Associate Security (CCNAS)	2011
Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA) CERT NO: 100-077-874	2008
(Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5)	
Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP)	2008
Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)	2008
Microsoft Certified System Administrator (MCSA) - Messaging	2008
Microsoft Certified System Administrator (MCSA)	2008
CompTIA Network+ Certified Professional	2008

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Operating System: windows Server 2000, 2003, 2008, 2012, 2016, XP, Vista, 7, 8, 10, Obuntu,

RHEL 5,6,7, CentOS 6,7, Debian, Mac OS X 10.6, Mac OS X Server 10.7, Raspberry Pi Jessie,

kali Linux, Unix, novel Netware

Hardware: Cisco Routers 3600, 3800, 7200, 7500 series, Cisco L2 & L3 Switches Nexus 2k,5k &

7k, Juniper Platforms M, J and MX Series Router, IBM pSeries Servers, HP & Dell Blade Servers, EMC Clarion SAN, ASA Firewall & VPN, CCTV MotionEye Surveillance

Cameras.

Software: Microsoft Project, Lotus Notes Clients and Server, Microsoft Lync, Exchange Server

2000, 2003, 2007, 2010, SCCM, Cisco IOS Seagate backup Exec, Norton, McAfee, MS Office Suite 2003, 2007, 2012, Open Office, PC Anywere, Corel Draw, Visio, Acrobat,

MS Project, WhatsUpGold, CRM, Vsphere, Esxi, XEN and Hyper- V technologies.

Cloud: PaaS (Amazon AWS & EC2, Microsoft Azure), SaaS (Salesforce.com, NetSuite)

Web Background: PHP, HTML/ CSS, Python, ASP.NET, Apache/Tomcat, Microsoft IIS, WebSphere,

LAMP Stack, SharePoint, Eclipse, Pycharm, komodo, Dream weaver, bootstrap, Web

Systems Administration (DevOps).

Databases: Generic SQL Programming, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, Microsoft SQL

Network/Protocol: LAN/WAN, TCP/IP, NWLINK, DNS, DHCP, POP3, SMTP, FTP, TELNET, ICMP, RIP,

IGRP, NAT, TFTP, EIGRP, OSPF, IS-IS, BGP, ETHERNET, NAS, RAS, SAMBA, SENDMAIL, RADIUS, TACACS+, MPLS, FRAME RELAY, IPSEC- VPN, REMOTE-ACCESS VPN, L2TP/PPTP, GRE, EASY VPN, WEBVPN, DMVPN, MPLS VPN

Security: Cisco Zone Base Firewall, Cisco PIX /Firewall, AAA Model (TACACs+, RADIUS,

Kerberos), Cisco IDS / IPS (Intrusion Detection / Prevention System), L2 security, ACLs, SPAM filtering by means of DNS blacklists, GFI mail Essentials, Cyberoam, SPF, domain keys, Rootkit and backdoor identification and removal, DOS and DDoS

defense. Virus-removal (adware, malware, worms. Etc.)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ingsoc International Limited

57 Oda Crescent, Wuse 2, Abuja. DURATION: January 2016 - Till date

POSITION: IT Manager

Employed as a full-time IT Manager following initial consulting role to manage and maintain a mixed server environment (Windows/Unix/Linux), ensuring 99.9% or better uptime. Evaluate, monitor and enhance IT infrastructure with an emphasis on availability, reliability, scalability, security, data confidentiality and system integrity.

Duties and Responsibilities

- Installed & Configured: Cisco Routers: 2800, 2600, 2500, 7200, 3600, Catalyst Switches: 6500, 5500, 4900, 3550, and 2900s and Nexus 7K, 5K and 2K switches.
- Strategically resolved complex issues involving OS X
- Developed object oriented PHP framework and built MySQL database and procedures.
- Built server hardware and set up web systems software (CentOS, Network, LAMP stack).
- Designing and implementing wireless architectures (Cisco Aironet APs and Cisco 4400 series controllers)
- Trained employees across multiple departments on network operations including log-in procedures, network management software, permissions, printing issues, security and use of software.
- Writing best practices and standards documentation for Windows Server 2012 R2 build out and deployment
- Monitor performance of network and servers to identify potential problems and bottleneck.
- Made use of Amazon Cloud's Simple Storage Service S3 and Elastic Cloud Computing (EC2)
- Identified areas of improvement within the technical infrastructure and designed solutions, including server consolidation opportunities on blades and virtualization with VMware ESXi.
- Hardening Cisco devices Implementing IDS and IPS, Cisco IOS Firewall and AAA.
- Ensure the continuous business operations through contingency planning and implementation and integrity through security administration.

Bayelsa State Government House

Office of the senior special assistant to the governor on data gathering and management

DURATION: February, 2012- October 2015 **POSITION: IT/Network Administrator** –

Managed IT infrastructure, Server setup and maintenance; backup and disaster recovery; remote network administration, desktop setup and maintenance, MySQL and MS SQL database administration and network printing configuration.

Duties and Responsibilities

Design, implementation and operational management of Linux infrastructure and routers.

- Involved in configuring Juniper routers such as MX 40, MX 80 series and Juniper switches like, EX3300, EX3400 series
- Implemented enhanced backup and recovery practices, spearheaded installation and configuration, including cabling, Server Configuration, security and testing.
- Resolved critical technical issues pertaining to System Performance, Viruses, Spyware and Spam related issues, Network & Internet Connectivity related issues, Application Conflicts & System Bugs.
- Took Lead on the implementation of Active Directory, Group Policy, DNS, DHCP, Ethernet, Anti-virus, Radius Servers.
- Documented upgradation procedures from Microsoft SQL to MySQL Server.
- Virtualization architecture deployment via KVM and Hyper-V, providing HA and decreasing footprint in Data Center.
- Managing the internal & hosted network infrastructure including: firewalls, servers, Cisco Router, switches and IP telephony.

Apptuweb Ltd

No 28 Tombia Street GRA Phase 1 Port Harcourt, Rivers State

DURATION: February, 2011 - February, 2012

POSITION: IT Manager

Duties and Responsibilities

- Monitoring and use of network management tools, server management tools & advanced troubleshooting skills in OS related issues.
- Architected n-tier infrastructures for application development projects consisting of AIX, and Linux Servers, WebSphere, web servers (Apache, IIS), PIX firewalls.
- Maintained & Configured Cisco Catalyst switches 2900, 3550, 3750 series switches and Cisco 2600, 2800, 3600 series routers
- Involved in Switching Technology Administration including creating and managing VLAN's, Port security, Trunking, GLBP, STP, LAN Security, and Inter Vlan Routing.
- Deploying & Administering Corporate Messaging Solutions for Customers based on Microsoft Technologies.
- Responsible for identifying, developing, implementing and maintaining high level industry standard security practices.
- Installed, configured and troubleshoot windows Server 2003/2008 Active Directory domain services for Clients.

Cobranet Limited (ISP)

Plot 8, Rafiu Babatunde Street, off Admiralty Way, Lekki Phase 1,

Lagos, Nigeria.

DURATION: Sept, 2009 – Feb, 2011

POSITION HELD: Corporate Support Coordinator /Technical Support Engineer

Hired as a Technical Support Engineer and promoted to a Corporate Support Coordinator. Worked with a proactive team of network support staff responsible for delivering a high quality, customer focused professional service, providing the highest level of network technical support and customer service to internal staff and client.

Duties and Responsibilities

- Monitor and provide assistance for Network /technical support team which is responsible for infrastructure services on Microsoft Windows OS, Linux Server, and Mac OS X.
- Involved in the configuration & troubleshooting of routing protocols: MP-BGP, OSPF, LDP, EIGRP, RIP, and BGP.
- Monitoring/Analysis of the internet Wireless network and bandwidth using PRTG Network Monitor, wireless (whatsUpGold) map monitor, BlueCoat Packet Shaper, Cacti.
- Respond to Customers inquiries and requests concerning Bandwidth usage/upgrade/downgrade, additional services, equipment like oxbridge radios, Ugo modems and providing solution.
- Installation and configuration of devices (Cisco switches 2960-3560 and routers 1700-7609) to extend network or functionality.
- Implement network security including Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS), Cisco PIX, Checkpoint FireWall-1 NG Firewalls, Cisco ACS Servers and VPNs for clients.

- Attending to clients problems and resolving technical problems on phone.
- Configuring IP Networking services as per the Client requirements. It Includes Configuring File & Print Servers, Mail servers (Send mail), DNS, WINS and DHCP both in Windows and UNIX environment.
- Implementing traffic engineering on top of an existing Multiprotocol Label Switching (MPLS) network using Frame Relay and Open Shortest Path First (OSPF).

Fibow Petroleum & Environmental Engineering Consult Limited

No 1 off -Choba Bridge, East-West Road, Isiudu Emohua. Rivers State

DURATION: Oct 2008 – Sept, 2009

POSITION HELD: SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Perform all duties related to Red hat Linux system administration, DNS, NFS, user account maintenance, backup & recovery, Auto-mounting, License Management, Printer configuration.
- Ensure the continuous business operations through contingency planning and implementation and integrity through security administration.
- Configuring Windows server 2003 Networks both in Workgroup Model and Enterprise Domain Model.
- Installing, Configuring and managing windows server 2003 Domain Controllers and Active Directory Services.
- Suggesting improvements in the operations and processes to make the system fail-safe.

NTX LIMITED

No 2 F.O.C Close Elenlenwo Street GRA, Phase 1

Port Harcourt. Rivers State

DURATION: May, 2005 – February, 2008

POSITION HELD: NETWORK SUPPORT ENGINEER

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Installing, configuring and Monitoring Network devices like Routers, Servers, Switches, Cisco PIX Firewall.
- Manage a cluster of Apache Server, Windows Internet Information Services server 6.0 (IIS 6) in a VMware Suse Linux environment
- Installation, repair and maintenance of PC hardware.
- Identified and resolve hardware and software technical problems and malfunctions related to both LANs/WANs, and related servers.
- Implementing and managing Microsoft Exchange Server 2003.

N.Y.S.C

NTX LIMITED

No 2 F.O.C Close, Elenlenwo Street GR A, Phase 1, Port Harcourt.

DURATION: February 2006 - January 2007

POSITION HELD: NETWORK SUPPORT ENGINEER

EARLY CAREER SUMMARY
Date of birth: April 9th 1980
Nationality: Nigerian
State: Bayelsa State

Gender: Male

INTEREST AND ACTIVITIES

Surfing the internet, writing, reading, meeting. people, playing football, Driving and listening music.







